## Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer Tallinn, Estonia

 $+372\ 511\ 1618$ konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

#### PROFILE

I have eight years of experience as a software developer, with a focus on Java. I commit to teamwork, building applications that undergo rigorous testing and seamless delivery. I love researching and staying updated with the latest technologies. I'm always searching for ways to improve my skills and make my work better.

### Programming Skills

• Programming Languages: Java, TypeScript, Python Hibernate, Junit, Mockito, WireMock

**Technologies:** Spring Boot, Angular, Vue,

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis Languages: English, Estonian, Russian

### EXPERIENCE

• Bankera Tallinn, Estonia Senior Software Engineer Jun 2022 - Present

o In my position on the Know Your Customer (KYC) team, I led the creation and upkeep of microservices using Spring Boot and Java (from versions 8 to 21). I used databases like Postgres and testing tools including Mockito, Wiremock, and Assert J. My work helped build strong, scalable, and effective solutions for complying

# • University of Tartu

Tartu, Estonia

Aug 2022 - Present Teaching Assistant

• Object Oriented Programming in Java

with financial services regulations.

- Web Application Development
- Enterprise System Integration

• Monese Tallinn, Estonia

 $Technical\ Lead\ Engineer$ 

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

- As a part of the Payments team, I was leading and refactoring a monolith into a single responsibility microservice.
- I was in charge of architecting a strong customer authentication (SCA PSD2) solution.

 Monese London, United Kingdom

Technical Lead Engineer

Jul 2020 - Sep 2021

• Reduced costs by systematically improving software performance and decreasing operating costs. For one application, its monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.

• Monese London, United Kingdom Mar 2019 - Jun 2020

Software Engineer

- o Increased revenue by identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a solution for a single customer led to the identification of a significant gap in profit.
- As a part of the Pricing team, delivered business priorities by completing a new, annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues. Additionally, I led research on breaking a monolithic application into a single responsibility microservice.
- As a part of the Joint Accounts team, I designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

 Monese Tallinn, Estonia

Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- As a part of the Smart Transactions team, I improved the scalability of micro-services by separating the read and write operation of the database.
- Successfully migrated 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. As a result, the average response time decreased from 60ms to 5ms.
- Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.

 $\circ$  As a part of the Recurring Payments team, I designed and developed a micro-service with a test coverage of up to 80%.

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

- As a part of the Banking team, I advocated for clean, robust, and maintainable code while promoting through code reviews, pair programming, and test-driven development.
- Increased the team's productivity by sharing my peers' development tricks.
- Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.

• Knowit

Tallinn, Estonia

Software Developer

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- o Employee of the Q4, 2016.
- $\circ\,$  Developed a full-stack, web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.

### **EDUCATION**

## • Tartu University

Estonia

Master of Engineering (MEng); Computer Science; GPA: 4.67/5;

- Master's Thesis "Developing a Web-Based Mini-Mental State Examination: Innovations in Accessibility and Efficiency for Cognitive Assessment"
- Achievement stipend
- Specialisation stipend

## • Tallinn University

Estonia

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (BSc); Computer Science; GPA: 4.73/5; cum laude

- o Bachelor's Thesis "The Development of a Self-study Web Application Using Angular and Spring Boot"
- Achievement stipend
- Specialisation stipend